Register of the Gann-Duignan Papers, 1911-2003
Hoover Institution Archives
- Incremental speeches and writings, 1954-2002
  - Op-eds, 1980-1993
    - South Africa, 1986-1989, undated (Box-folder 132: 5-7)
      Includes typescripts of "The Coming Summit," Do Not Support the ANC Unless It Changes," "Germany's Future," "Governor Deukmejian," "Should the U.S. Provide a Marshall Plan for Eastern Europe," "South Africa and the Next Twelve Months," "South Africa: War, Revolution, or Peace?" "South Africa: A Revolutionary Situation?" "South Africa: What's To Be Done?" and "The US and South Africa"
    - Published
      - Africa, 1986-1991 (Box-folder 132: 8)
      - Domestic, 1989 (Box-folder 132: 9)
      - International, 1989-1993 (Box-folder 132: 10)
      - History of Hoover, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 132: 11)
    - Submitted and published, 1993 (Box-folder 132: 12)
    - Submitted
      - Africa, 1988, undated (Box-folder 132: 13)
        Includes typescripts of "The Economic Debate in South Africa," "Mandela's Visit to the U.S.," "Reforms in South Africa," and "The South African Elections"
      - Domestic, 1992, undated (Box-folder 132: 14)
        Includes typescripts of "Academe: Apologies Are Due," "Lest We Forget: The Flawed Academic Left," and "The U.S. Is Not in Decline,"
      - Eastern Europe, 1989, undated (Box-folder 132: 15)
        Includes typescripts of "1789 and 1989: Two Revolutions," "Can Communism Be Reformed?" "Don't Be Afraid to Negotiate With the Soviets," "The Future of NATO," "Germany's Future," "Let's Have Glasnost in the West About Communism," and "Should the U.S. Provide a Marshall Plan for Eastern Europe?"
      - Europe, 1990 (Box-folder 132: 16)
        Includes typescripts of "The East German Election," "German Reunification," "Lessons for Lithuanians and Americans," " Regain the Diplomatic Initiative," "The U.S. and NATO," and "Will it be Deutschland Uber Alles Again?"
      - International, undated (Box-folder 132: 17)
        Includes typescript of "Gulf War Reflections"
  - Printed copies, 1978-1994
    Contains clippings of articles by Gann and Duignan. See also chronological file
    - 1978-1980 (Box-folder 157: 1)
    - 1981 (Box-folder 157: 2)
    - 1982 (Box-folder 157: 3)
    - 1983 (Box-folder 157: 4)
    - 1984 (Box-folder 157: 5)
    - 1985 (Box-folder 157: 6)
    - 1986 (Box-folder 157: 7)
    - 1987-1988 (Box-folder 157: 8)
    - 1989-1994 (Box-folder 157: 9-10)
- Incremental subject file, 1953-1995
  Includes research material and notes on Africa, the United States, colonialism, and Spanish speakers.
  - Africa
    - General, 1953-1992 (Box 80, 152, 168-169)
    - Notes, 1960-1966 (Box 154-155)
      Includes lecture outlines and printed matter
  - Africa, Cold War, Middle East, Soviet Union, and miscellaneous, 1979-1995 (Box 107, 159)
  - African and American immigration (Box 152)
  - Colonialism, 1969-1994 (Box 90)
  - France and Germany, 1973-1995 (Box 100)
  - Germany, 1979-1991 (Box 108-109)
  - Guerrilla warfare, insurgency, and terrorism, 1980-1989 (Box 80)
  - Politics, policy issues, and economy, 1985-1996 (Box 104)
  - Rhodesia, 1966-1975, undated (Box 111)
  - Spanish speakers, immigrants, and Latin America, 1973-1983 (Box 111-116)
  - United States, 1978-1994 (Box 97)
- Incremental professional activities file, 1961-2003
  Includes material documenting Gann and Duignan's career at the Hoover Institution, including activities involving the European Studies and International Studies programs. Includes documentation of involvement in various committees, boards, and organizations, as well as speaking engagement files and teaching files.
  - General, 1979-1997
    - 1996-1997 (Box-folder 147: 1)
      Includes condolence letters
    - "African History Since 1945," course materials, undated (Box-folder 147: 2)
    - Rowen, Harry, 1979 (Box-folder 147: 3)
    - World Media Association fact finding trip to Pretoria, notebook, 1987 (Box-folder 147: 4)
  - Peter Duignan file, 1961-2003
    Includes conferences and speaking engagements of Duignan, committee and organization material, and meeting minutes of the Society for the Promotion of Science and Scholarship (SPOSS)
    - General, 1987-2003 (Box-folder 147: 5-7)
    - The Atlantic Council, 1985-1999 (Box-folder 147: 8-10)
    - Author's registry, 2002 (Box-folder 147: 11)
    - Biographical information, 1985-1990 (Box-folder 147: 12)
    - Carman, Charles, 1990 (Box-folder 147: 13)
    - Carnegie Leadership Conference, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 147: 14)
    - Churchill Club, 1999 (Box-folder 147: 15)
    - CIPE (Center for International Private Enterprise), 1986-1988 (Box-folder 147: 16)
    - Clippings on Duignan, 1961, 1988 (Box-folder 148: 1)
    - Committees and centers
      - Centre for European Policy Studies, 1987 (Box-folder 148: 2)
      - Committee on African Studies, 1989-1994 (Box-folder 148: 3-4)
      - Joint Center for African Studies, Stanford and Berkeley, 1990 (Box-folder 148: 5)
      - Stanford Center for European Studies, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 148: 6)
      - Stanford Institute of International Studies, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 148: 7)
      - Stanford Committee on South Africa, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 148: 8)
    - Conference file
      - General, 1987-1993 (Box-folder 148: 9-11)
      - Germany, Harvard University, "1949-1989: The Federal Republic As History" (Box-folder 148: 12)
      - University of Hull, England, "European Unity in Context", 1989 (Box-folder 148: 13)
    - Defense of Democracy Trust, 1993 (Box-folder 148: 14)
    - European Institute, Washington D.C., 1990 (Box-folder 148: 15)
    - Fluor Utah, Inc., 1975 (Box-folder 148: 16)
    - Ford Foundation proposals, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 148: 17-18)
    - German Historical Institute, 1989 (Box-folder 148: 19)
    - Great War Society, 1996 (Box-folder 148: 20)
    - Hilton, Ronald conference, World Association of International Studies, 2001 (Box-folder 148: 21)
    - Institute for Advanced Studies, Princeton, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 148: 22)
    - Hurewitz, J.C. papers, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 148: 23)
    - Intercollegiate Studies Institute, 1986 (Box-folder 148: 24)
    - International Freedom Foundation, 1987 (Box-folder 148: 25)
    - Iran conferences, 1989, 1993 (Box-folder 148: 26-27)
    - Journal Editorship (Box-folder 149: 1)
    - Lewis and Clark College, "Colonialism in Africa" course, circa 1965-1966 (Box-folder 149: 2)
    - Mont Pèlerin Society, 1984-1986 (Box-folder 149: 3)
    - Mueller, Adria, 2001 (Box-folder 149: 4)
    - Marcus, Harold Festschrift, 1993 (Box-folder 149: 5)
    - National Bureau of Economic Research, 1992-1996 (Box-folder 149: 6)
    - NBC, Belafonte project, 1986 (Box-folder 149: 7)
    - Political Science and European Unification newsletter, 1990 (Box-folder 149: 8)
    - Praise file, 1986 (Box-folder 149: 9)
    - Princeton Institute for Advanced Study, 1988 (Box-folder 149: 10)
    - Queen Elizabeth's house, 1983-1985 (Box-folder 149: 11)
    - Permission requests, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 149: 12)
    - Republican Associates, 1986 (Box-folder 149: 13)
    - Royal Historical Society, 1994-1998 (Box-folder 149: 14)
    - Richards, I. A., undated (Box-folder 149: 15)
    - San Jose State teaching file, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 149: 16)
    - Seminar invitation, 1986 (Box-folder 149: 17)
    - Society for the Promotion of Science and Scholarship (SPOSS), 1984-2001 (Box-folder 149: 18-21)
    - Society for the Promotion of Science and Scholarship (SPOSS) (Contd.) (Box-folder 92: 1-3)
    - Stanford Alumni Association (Box-folder 92: 4)
    - Tikhman, Simon, 2001 (Box-folder 92: 5)
    - Travel file
      - African safari, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 92: 6)
      - Botswana trip, 1993 (Box-folder 92: 7)
      - Brussels, 1991 (Box-folder 92: 8)
      - Florence, Italy, Stanford campus abroad, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 92: 9)
      - Middle East trip, 1979 (Box-folder 92: 10-11)
      - South Africa travel, World Media, 1987 (Box-folder 92: 12)
    - Uncommon Book Award, 1997-1999, 2002 (Box-folder 92: 13-14)
    - Urban Institute, 1996 (Box-folder 92: 15)
    - Visitors, Gariela Tarazona-Sevillano proposal, undated (Box-folder 92: 16)
    - Voice of America, 2001 (Box-folder 92: 17)
    - Westview Press, 1984-1994 (Box-folder 92: 18)
    - "Wither South Africa", 1988 (Box-folder 92: 19)
    - World Encyclopaedia of Peace, Pergamon Press, Oxford, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 92: 20)
    - World Media Association, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 92: 21)
    - World War II conference, 1995 (Box-folder 92: 22)
    - Xerox project, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 92: 23)
  - Lewis Gann file, 1965-1997
    - General, 1986-1989 (Box-folder 105: 1)
    - American Council of Learned Societies, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 105: 2)
    - Award file, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 105: 3)
    - Clipping on Gann, 1993 (Box-folder 105: 4)
    - Conference file
      - 1986 (Box-folder 105: 5)
      - 1987 (Box-folder 105: 6)
      - 1988 (Box-folder 105: 7)
      - 1988-1989 (Box-folder 105: 8)
      - 1992 (Box-folder 105: 9)
      - 1992-1993 (Box-folder 105: 10)
      - 1995-1996 (Box-folder 105: 11)
    - German Jews, research and correspondence, 1965-1969 (Box-folder 105: 12)
    - Letters from Gann, 1986, undated (Box-folder 171: 1)
      Originally labeled: Letters L.H.G. got off his chest (but didn't necessarily mail)
    - Lewis and Clark College, summer courses, 1968, 1975 (Box-folder 171: 2)
    - Mozambique, Portugal, and Angola notebooks, 1974 (Box-folder 171: 3)
    - Princeton Institute for Advanced Study, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 171: 4)
    - Recommendation for Duignan, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 171: 5)
    - Schroeder,Klaus, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 171: 6)
    - Teaching file, 1965-1969 (Box-folder 171: 7)
    - "U.S. National Security in the 1980s," IR course, 1983 (Box-folder 171: 8)
    - Widmaier, Hans Peter, 1994-1997 (Box-folder 171: 9-11)
  - Hoover Institution, 1965-2000
    - Activities reports, 1980-1986 (Box-folder 144: 1)
    - Administrative file, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 144: 2)
    - African Program, 1971, undated (Box-folder 144: 3)
    - Controversy file, 1983-1988 (Box-folder 144: 4-6)
    - Curatorial aides, Africana, 1969 (Box-folder 144: 7)
    - European Studies
      - General, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 144: 8)
      - Barnes, Samuel H., 1992-2000 (Box-folder 144: 9)
      - Centers and programs, 1989 (Box-folder 144: 10)
      - Diplomacy series, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 144: 11)
      - European lectures, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 145: 1-2)
      - German panels, 1990 (Box-folder 145: 3)
      - Kennan, George visit, diplomacy series, 1989 (Box-folder 145: 4)
      - Politics and culture series, 1989 (Box-folder 145: 5)
      - "Report on the European Studies Group and African/Middle East Studies Programs at the Hoover Institution", 1989 (Box-folder 145: 6)
      - Roundtable on German Reunification, 1990 (Box-folder 145: 7)
      - Schmitter list, European studies centers, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 145: 8)
      - Talks and seminars, 1991-1993 (Box-folder 145: 9)
      - Western European Studies, 1986-1993 (Box-folder 145: 10)
    - German Studies, 1985, 1992-1994 (Box-folder 145: 11)
    - Hoover Institution Press, undated (Box-folder 145: 12)
    - Inquiries file, correspondence, 1965-1969 (Box-folder 145: 13)
    - International Studies
      - General, 1973, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 145: 14-15)
      - Alphabetical and geographical lists, 1985 (Box-folder 145: 16)
      - Correspondence, 1982-1989 (Box-folder 145: 17-18)
      - Duignan, Peter, 1984-1989 (Box-folder 89: 1)
      - Future fellow possibilities, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 89: 2)
      - Historiography, undated (Box-folder 89: 3)
      - Memoranda, 1983-1990 (Box-folder 89: 4)
      - Newsletters, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 89: 5)
      - Paret, Peter, 1989 (Box-folder 89: 6)
      - Search committee, 1987-2000 (Box-folder 89: 7)
      - Status reports, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 89: 8)
    - Lecture series and conferences, 1989 (Box-folder 89: 9)
    - Project Africa, undated (Box-folder 89: 10)
    - Reports on Africa collection and research, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 89: 11)
    - Reports and proposals, undated (Box-folder 89: 12)
    - Stanford campus map, undated (Box-folder 89: 13)
    - Visiting scholars
      - General, 1990-1993 (Box-folder 89: 14-15)
      - Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 89: 16)
      - Chiswick, Barry R., 1986 (Box-folder 89: 17)
      - Distinguished Visiting Professors Program
        - Central and Eastern Europe, lecture notes, 1994 (Box-folder 89: 18)
        - Embattled Empire: From Soviet Union to C.I.S., lecture notes, 1994 (Box-folder 89: 19)
        - "The Post Cold War World," lecture notes, undated (Box-folder 89: 20)
        - Schedule of Duignan, circa 1994 (Box-folder 89: 21)
      - Keegan, John, 1984 (Box-folder 118: 1)
      - McNamara, Francis, 1983-1986 (Box-folder 118: 2)
      - Middlemas, Keith, research project correspondence, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 118: 3)
      - Nicol, Davidson, 1983-1989 (Box-folder 118: 4)
      - Talks by visitors, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 118: 5)
- Incremental photographs, 1982, undated
  Includes images of Lübeck, Germany, and Soweto, an area in Johannesburg, South Africa.
  - Photographic prints of Lübeck, Germany, 1982 (Box-folder 118: 6)
    Photographs sent to Peter Duignan from Jeffry M. Diefendorf
  - Slides of Soweto, South Africa, undated (Box-folder 118: 7)
- Incremental card file, undated
  Includes a bibliography with notes on and quotes from works concerning Africa and a file of short biographies.
  - General, undated (Box 119-125)
  - Africa bibliography and notes, undated (Box 126-130)
  - Biographical sketches, undated (Box 165-166)
- Incremental oversize material
  Includes photocopied documents of the British Foreign Office. See also speeches and writings for oversize galleys.
  - British Foreign Office, photocopied documents from late 1800s (Box 131)
  - Map of Africa in 1971 (Box 173)
    Originally filed with maps and photographs in box 53
- Incremental sound recordings, 1977
  Includes cassette tapes containing interviews with members of the South West Africa People's Organization (SWAPO).
  - University of Fort Hare, Ciskei, undated (Box 174)
    One cassette tape
  - "Poquind, Biks, colored leaders, Van Der Herst", undated (Box 174)
  - Interview with Peter [Katjavivi] on South West Africa People's Organization (SWAPO), London, 1977 June 3 (Box 174)
  - Sheena Duncan, 1977 June 7 (Box 174)
  - A. Kerena, Windhoek, Namibia, 1977 June 21 (Box 174)
  - Emil Appolus, editor of Times of Namibia and leader of SWAPO, 1977 June 20 (Box 174)
  - Interview with D. Tjongarero, deputy chief of SWAPO, 1977 June 22 (Box 174)